datascienceplus.com 2019-05-26

# Privacy Policy | DataScience+

Your privacy is critically important to us. At DataSciencePlus.com we have a few fundamental principles:

  1. We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.
  2. We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  3. We store personal information for only as long as we have a reason to keep it.

### Information We Collect

We only collect information about you if we have a reason to do so–for example, to provide our Services, to communicate with you, or to make our Services better.

We collect information in three ways: if and when you provide information to us, automatically through operating our services, and from outside sources. Let’s go over the information that we collect.

#### Information You Provide to Us

We collect your Personal Information directly from you when you fill in forms on DataSciencePlus.com. For example, we may obtain your Personal Information when you create an account, comment, or use contact forms.

Personal Information may include:  
– user name;  
– email address;

optional or only for authors:  
– first and last name;  
– job title;  
– profile picture;  
– social links;  
– expertise or interests;  
– country.

#### Information We Collect Automatically

We also collect some information automatically.

 **Log Information:** Like most online service providers, we collect information that web browsers, mobile devices, and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, IP address, unique device identifiers, language preference, referring site, the date and time of access, operating system, and mobile network information.

 **Usage Information:** We collect information about your usage of our Services. For example, we collect information about the actions that users perform on a site–in other words, who did what, when and to what thing on a site (e.g., [WordPress username] created/edited/deleted “[title of post]” at [time/date]). We also collect information about what happens when you use our Services (e.g., page views) along with information about your device (e.g., mobile screen size, name of cellular network, and mobile device manufacturer). We use this information to, for example, provide our Services to you, as well as get insights on how people use our Services, so we can make our Services better.

 **Location Information:** We may determine the approximate location of your device from your IP address. We collect and use this information to, for example, calculate how many people visit our Services from certain geographic regions.

 **Information from Cookies & Other Technologies:** A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. DataSciencePlus.com visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using DataSciencePlus.com websites, with the drawback that certain features of DataSciencePlus.com websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

#### Information We Collect from Other Sources

We may also get information about you from other sources. For example, we use Gravatar.com service to obtain an avatar (profile picture) automatically for authors and to show along with their articles.

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. In addition, we use Disqus to provide the comments and discussion board on our website.

The Gravatar Privacy Policy:  
<https://automattic.com/privacy/>.

Disqus Privacy Policy:  
<https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/466259-privacy-policy>

#### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

#### Contact forms

We use the [Contact Form 7 plugin](https://wordpress.org/plugins/contact-form-7/) to manage contact form submissions on our website. When you send a message to us or our authors of via contact forms, the information is stored in the database on our hosting server for backup and later reference purposes. We use the [Flamingo plugin](https://wordpress.org/plugins/flamingo/) to safely manage this data.

We may choose to delete the messages we receive via contact forms on a regular basis, however, don’t set a particular time limit on storing information because we might need it for future reference. If you want your data to be removed from our database, please contact us, and we will remove immediately.

### Ads and Analytics Services Provided by Others

Ads appearing on any of our Services may be delivered by advertising networks or our Authors (affiliation links or banners, i.e., DataCamp). Other parties may also provide analytics services via our Services. These ad networks (i.e., Google Adsense and BuySellAds) and analytics providers (i.e., Google Analytics and Statcounter) may set tracking technologies (like cookies) to collect information about your use of our Services and across other websites and online services. These technologies allow these third parties to recognize your device to compile information about you or others who use your device. This information allows us and other companies to, among other things, analyze and track usage, determine the popularity of certain content, and deliver advertisements that may be more targeted to your interests. Please note this Privacy Policy only covers the collection of information by DataSciencePlus.com and does not cover the collection of information by any third party advertisers or analytics providers.

Google Analytics Privacy Policy:  
<https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

Statcounter Provate Policy:  
<https://statcounter.com/about/legal/#privacy>

Google Adsense Privacy Policy:  
<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl=en>

DataCamp Privacy Policy:  
https://www.datacamp.com/privacy-policy

### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can [request to receive](https://datascienceplus.com/personal-data-request/) an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Sharing Information

We do not sell our users’ private personal information. However, we do use some WordPress plugins on DataSciencePlus.com that may pass data, including personal information, to external servers to process, such as Akismet Anti-Spam. We only use WordPress plugins that are hosted by WordPress.org. WordPress.org’s guidelines prohibit tracking users without their explicit informed consent.

Akismet Anti-Spam Privacy Policy:  
<https://automattic.com/privacy-notice/>

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, DataSciencePlus.com may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in DataSciencePlus.com sole discretion. DataSciencePlus.com encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

 _Updated October 1, 2018_

 _This Privacy Policy was based on[Wordpress.com](https://automattic.com/privacy/) and [Wordpress.org](https://wordpress.org/about/privacy/) versions._
